The active life cycle is when your activity is in the foreground and
has focus. Here it is actively receiving input from user events and
no other activities are obscuring it. On [UNKNOWN] and
the active lifetime ends as soon as your activity is partially obscured,
like in this example. [SOUND] You can see here the permissions dialogue
is displayed in front of Google Play for
an app in store. Or the same thing happens when you have another activity trying
to fulfill an implicit intent and the user needs to make a selection. So
to make efficient use of limited resources,
you'll want to use these signals to adjust your app's resource burden.
So, most updates through a UI, can be paused when this lifetime ends,
which is announced by onPause. But as you see, the app is still visible, so
you shouldn't pause any processes that are drawing your UI. The visible
lifetime on the other hand continues whenever the app is at all visible and
ends as soon as it's completely obscured by another app. Like this.
[SOUND] At this point, our app is moved to the background.
So when you see on stop, you know the user can't see your app at all. So, while
OnCreate and OnDestroy will be called at most once, each time your app is run,
these handlers are likely to be called many times, while the app is running.
Now, this is where things get a little different. On almost al platforms,
app life cycles are deterministic. Generally, you'll start a program and
it'll keep running, until it either completes or the user cancels it. You look
at traditional desktop development that means your app keeps running until your
user chooses quit or exit from the file menu. At that point you can say stay and
free resources. But as we know on Android life cycles work a little differently.
So, let's take a closer look at exactly how that works now.